# **Kevin Carmody**

Born 21st December 1979

07870 332981

kevin@skinofstars.com skinofstars.com/experience github.com/skinofstars

I am a good communicator, enthusiastic, enjoy a challenge and eager to learn. I have been developing for the Internet since 2001 and in this time I have built up a wide skill base which I am keen to share with my team. I have been a professional developer since 2009.

# Key competent technologies

### Languages

- Ruby
- PHP
- JavaScript
- HTML5/CSS3
- XSLT
- Bash
- Python

#### **Frameworks**

- Ruby on Rails
- Symfony
- Silex
- Phonegap/Cordova
- KnockoutJS
- ExpressJS
- Wordpress
- Mediawiki
- Movable Type

#### **Databases**

- MySQL
- CouchDB
- MongoDB
- Elasticsearch
- SQLite
- Various browser/mobile databases

#### **Devops**

- Linux sysadmin
- Ansible
- AWS
- Capistrano
- Continuous deployment
- Node.js

## Professional experience

#### **Technical Development Manager - Smart Editors**

March 2014 - Present

I was asked to manage a team that would look after, develop and expand a legacy Ruby on Rails system, as well as develop new products and work on growing the business.

From the outset I trained the team in modern software business practices, like Agile and Lean. I was quickly able to get them creating software to realistic time estimates whilst ensuring they adhered to best practices, like Test Driven Development and Continuous Deployment. I have also done extensive work on defining the company's business strategy going in to the future.

#### Web Developer - White October

March 2010 - September 2013 (3 years 7 months)

An Agile digital media agency where I got to work on numerous types of projects. Team sizes tended to range from 1 to 3 developers. Time on a project could be up to 10 months.

Extensive use of Symfony2 in developing high availability backends, using TDD and BDD (PHPUnit and Behat) best practices. Design and implementation of system architectures for large scale JS applications, including a high profile KnockoutJS on PhoneGap application now used by 200k+ users.

I developed several multistage Continuous Deployment and Continuous Integration strategies, which became company standards.

## Web Developer - Studio Lift

September 2009 – March 2010 (7 months)

Within this progressive design studio, i was implementing frontend HTML5 and CSS3 as well as developing using Movable Type, a static build platform for high availability sites

I am happy to talk about specific sites and projects I have worked on when we meet.

## Other experience

I'm one of those geeks that loves this stuff. I develop sites through the day, I run geek events in the evenings and weekends, and I go home and relax by playing with new tech.

Before becoming a professional developer, I spent most of my spare time as a hobbyist making sites for various community groups, running blogs and forums, including some quite large scale integrated systems.

I have run several hack days, including ones for Random Hacks of Kindness and the Open Data Day. I am also a co-founder of JS Oxford user group, whose meetings I have spoken at several times.

I have also been invited as an associate lecturer for a web development module at Oxford Brookes University.

I have given talks in the following areas:

- Using Ansible to quickly and reliably prepare and provision servers
- An introduction for newcomers to setting up and developing Node.js applications
- A simultaneous multi-platform Node.js+WebSockets game a friend and I developed.
- A comparison of JS frameworks (KnockoutJS, Backbone.js & AngularJS)
- Using D3.js to graphically represent relations within the Whedonverse
- Building IRC bots in Node.js
- Using KnockoutJS with CouchDB to painlessly create live updating UIs

## Other work experience

## **Coffee Shop Manager** June 2005 – November 2005

I was asked to manage a café. The business was soon breaking even and heading well into profitability with a regular customer base. I believe this to be because of my demand for high standards and encouraging the staff to communicate and develop their own ideas.

#### Homeless Intervention Worker June 2003 – June 2005

As a project worker for a homelessness charity, I was part of a team running Emergency Night Shelters and Supported Housing projects. I was often having to resolve potentially volatile situations which required clear communication skills.

### Formal education

**Undergraduate: Oxford Brookes University 2006 - 2009** 

First Class Honours - BSc Multimedia Systems and Communication, Media & Culture

**Higher Education: Canterbury College 2005 - 2006** 

Access course covering Psychology, Sociology and Politics.

## **Interests**

Outside of technology, I started to learn the bass guitar and six string at the age of fourteen. I was often coordinating practices, promotions and gigs. I also spent a great deal of time in promoting the music community as a whole. On moving to Oxford I expanded my community involvement by organising regular campus events for the Students Union. I was soon voted in to become the campus president.

As well as music I also enjoy juggling, mainly because of the pleasure in learning the skills involved and the mental focus required to attain a good standard.